onetime.com 2014-06-29

# OneTime Privacy Policy - OneTime.com

_This Privacy Policy was last changed February 16, 2011._

 **Overview**

The following Privacy Policy explains how OneTime.com. ("OneTime") gathers and uses personal information that is provided by our customers. Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time and OneTime reserves the right to change or modify our Privacy Policy at any time with or without notice.

_OneTime is committed to safeguarding your privacy. We do not rent or sell our customer database or newsletter subscriber list to third parties._ We do not share customer information in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement.

If you have any questions or concerns over the OneTime Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact [privacy@onetime.com](mailto:privacy@onetime.com).

By accessing a OneTime publication or by subscribing to a OneTime newsletter, you agree to our current [Terms of Use](http://www.onetime.com/terms.php).

**Site Registration, E-mail Subscriptions, E-mail Communications and Newsletters**

OneTime's registration form may require users to provide basic contact and demographic information. We use or may use your contact information (such as email address) from the registration form to send you newsletters and occasional information about our services and partners, inform you if you are the potential winner of a contest or promotion, personalize your experience with OneTime, or investigate cases of suspected fraud or abuse. You may opt-out of receiving future communications; see the Opting-Out of Further Communications section below. 

In the future, in order to customize your experience with our email newsletters, we may receive a confirmation when you open email from OneTime if your computer supports such capabilities. Clicking on a link in a OneTime newsletter may also be tracked on a per user basis to allow us to present content, which closely matches your interests. Demographic and profile data (such as state, zip code, age, or gender) may be used to customize your experience at our site or in our email newsletters, showing you content and advertising that may best suit your needs. This information is shared with advertisers and other third parties on an aggregate basis only. _Individually identifiable user click behavior is never shared with advertisers and partners._

If, in the future, you enter OneTime via a reward or incentive program, OneTime may share your email address with the program through which you entered OneTime to ensure you are credited with your incentive. 

You may also register for OneTime and/or specific OneTime newsletters at web sites operated by third parties. These third parties may share contact, demographic or profile data that you voluntarily provide during the registration process with OneTime. You also may provide personal information to third parties when you register at a third party web site and specifically request that your information be forwarded to us so that we can send you information about our product and service offerings. OneTime does or may in the future use this information in the same manner as information collected directly by OneTime. This Privacy Policy does not bind sites that collect information on behalf of OneTime, and OneTime is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. 

To better serve you, we may also store information you present to us via email or telephone communications with OneTime's Customer Service Department. This information is or may be used in the same manner as information directly collected using OneTime's registration form. We may also use information you provide us via email or telephone to pursue the matter for which you contacted us. OneTime also may obtain information from you in our online forums. This information may not be disclosed except as consistent with Terms of Use. 

In order to better communicate with registered users about their registration status, OneTime may acquire information about users from third-party sources, including but not limited to a users mailing address. The information collected will only be shared, if at all, on an aggregate basis only with third parties. 

**Display of Advertising/Your Choices**

_Data collected to serve you with relevant advertising_

OneTime and its affiliated websites are committed to providing you with relevant content and information across our sites. To do this, we may collect information about your travel-related searches, such as whether you are looking for airline flights or hotels, and use this information to serve you with ads on our sites or elsewhere online that match your apparent interests. So, for example, if you search for a flight to Florida on OneTime.com, you may see an ad for a Florida travel package on OneTime.com or on another website you visit. 

We do not share your personal information (such as email addresses) with unaffiliated third parties so they can serve you with advertisements. You can choose not to receive relevant online advertising on other Web sites, based on your travel-related searches on OneTime.com by clicking [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). 

_Data collected by business partners and ad networks to serve you with relevant advertising_

Many of the advertisements you see on the OneTime and Smarter Travel family of sites are served by OneTime.com or its service providers. But we also allow third parties to collect information about your online activities through cookies and other technologies. These third parties include (1) business partners, who collect information when you view or interact with one of their advertisements on our sites, and (2) advertising networks, who collect information about your interests when you view or interact with one of the advertisements they place on many different Web sites on the Internet. The information gathered by these third parties is used to make predictions about your characteristics, interests or preferences and to display advertisements on our sites and across the Internet tailored to your apparent interests. 

Please note that we do not have access to or control over cookies or other technologies these third parties may use to collect information about your interests, and the information practices of these third parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy. Some of these companies are members of the Network Advertising Initiative, which offers a single location to opt out of ad targeting from member companies. To learn more, please click here. 

__Data collected by companies that operate cookie-based exchanges to serve you with relevant advertising.__

Like other companies operating online, OneTime participates in cookie-based exchanges where anonymous information is collected about your browsing behavior through cookies and other technologies and segmented into different topics of interest (such as travel). These topics of interest are then shared with third parties, including advertisers and ad networks, so they can tailor advertisements to your apparent interests. We do not share personal information (such as your email address) with these companies and we do not permit these companies to collect any such information about you on our site. Please click [here](http://www.bluekai.com/consumers_optout.php) to learn more about cookie-based exchanges, including how to access information about the topics of interest associated with cookies on your computer and how to decline participation in these programs.

**What information we collect from you**

_Automatic Information_. We automatically collect some information about your computer when you visit OneTime. For example, we will collect your IP address, and information relating to your Web browser software (such as Netscape Navigator or Internet Explorer) and referring Web site. We also may collect information about your online activity, such as trips viewed. One of our goals in collecting this information is to help customize your user experience. We do not use this information to identify you.

_Cookies and Other Web Technologies_. When you visit OneTime, we may assign your computer a "cookie" (a small, unique identifier text file). You can always choose not to receive a cookie file by enabling your Web browser to refuse cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie. Please note that if you refuse to accept cookies from OneTime, you may not be able to access many of the travel tools offered by OneTime.

_Information Collected Through Web Analytics_. OneTime uses a Web analytics company to track and generate reports on visitor use of our site. We use the Web analytics company to analyze visitor activity so that we may better understand how visitors make use of OneTime, and so that we may better tailor content to meet our visitors' needs. This data may include anonymized, individual visitor click behavior. No personally identifiable information is obtained or shared with the Web analytics company. Although our Web analytics company logs the information coming from OneTime on our behalf, we control how that data may and may not be used. Visitors who wish to opt-out of this Web site analysis tool may do so by clicking [here](http://www.omniture.com/privacy/optout.html).

**How we use this information**

OneTime uses information we collect for the following general purposes: to measure interest in and improve our products, services, and Web site; to resolve disputes or troubleshoot problems; to prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities; to enforce our Terms of Use; and as otherwise described to you at the point of collection.

If you chose to receive communications from OneTime about special promotions when registering as a OneTime member, we may use your email address to send you communications about surveys, contests, sweepstakes, promotions, flight specials, deals or other travel news and opportunities on OneTime and its marketing partners. If you choose to receive our Newsletters, you may receive communications such as "Top Travel Deals" and periodic announcements about changes to our features at your email address. You can discontinue your subscription to OneTime promotional email services at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the email received or by going to OneTime and clicking on the 'Change Subscriptions' link on that page. You can also unsubscribe to e-mail communications at any time by replying to the email with the word "unsubscribe" in the subject line.

**With whom we share this information**

OneTime may share the information it collects with the following entities:

  * Third-party vendors who provide services or functions on our behalf, including package delivery, business analytics, customer service, marketing, distribution of surveys or sweepstakes programs, and fraud prevention. These companies have access to information needed to perform their functions but are not permitted to share or use the information for any other purpose.
  * Business partners who may offer products or services through our site. You can tell when a third party is involved in a product or service you have requested because their name will be listed. Please note that we do not control the privacy practices of these third-party business partners and recommend you evaluate their practices before deciding to provide them with any personal information.
  * Companies within the Expedia family. OneTime is a member of the Expedia corporate family. We may share information with our U.S. corporate affiliates, including Hotels.com, TripAdvisor, Hotwire, Cruise Critic, Travelpod, Holiday Lettings, FlipKey, DaoDao, Kuxun, Venere and Classic Vacations, as well as international corporate affiliates such as Expedia.com, TripAdvisor.com, and Expedia.de. To the extent that our corporate affiliates have access to your information, they will follow practices that are at least as restrictive as the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

We also may share your information:

  * In response to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases we reserve the right to raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us.
  * When we believe it is appropriate to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities; to protect and defend the rights, property, or safety of OneTime, our customers, or others; and in connection with our Terms of Service and other agreements.
  * In connection with a corporate transaction, such as a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.

Other than as set out above, you will be notified when information about you will be shared with third parties, and you will have an opportunity to choose not to have us share such information.

  * We also may share aggregate or anonymous information with third parties, including advertisers and investors. For example, we may tell our advertisers the number of visitors a Web site receives or what are the most popular vacation destinations. This information does not contain any personal information and is used to develop content and services we hope you will find of interest.
  * Occasionally, OneTime may participate in reward programs. In order to properly credit you for your reward, we may share basic customer information with the reward-giver
  * In the future, OneTime may host content on behalf of certain other web site partners. Information collected on these pages may be shared with the partner site. These pages, and any information shared with the partner site, are subject to the Privacy Policy of the partner site. 

**Sweepstakes, Online Surveys, and Order Forms**

OneTime occasionally runs sweepstakes, hosts online surveys, or uses order forms on our web site in which we ask for contact and demographic information. Participation in sweepstakes and surveys and usage of order forms is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. We use or may use your contact information (such as email address) from your sweepstakes entry, survey registration, or order form to inform you if you are the potential winner of a contest or promotion, personalize your experience with OneTime, send you newsletters (should you opt-in for these newsletters) and occasional information about our services or partners, or investigate cases of suspected fraud. You may opt-out of receiving future communications; see the Opting-Out of Further Communications section below. 

Demographic and profile data (such as zip code, age, or gender) may be used to customize your experience at our site, showing you content and advertising that may best suit your needs. This information is shared with advertisers and other third parties on an aggregate basis only. In the event that OneTime partners with a third party to run a sweepstakes, OneTime may share demographic and profile data with such third party only as indicated in the official sweepstakes rules. 

**Tell-a-Friend and Email This Deal**

OneTime may, from time to time, offer services to allow our users to send information about our site to their friends. If a user elects to use such service for informing a friend about our site, or elects to use our other services to inform a friend about information on our site, we will ask them for the friend's email address. We will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit our site. We store this information for the purpose of sending this one-time email and investigating suspected fraud. 

**Children Under 13 Years Old**

OneTime and its affiliated sites do not knowingly collect, maintain or use personal information from our websites about children under age 13. Children under the age of 13 may not participate in any online activities on Smarter Travel Media LLC's web sites. If a child whom we know to be under age 13 sends personal information to us online, we will only use that information to respond directly to that child, notify parents, or seek parental consent.

**IP Addresses**

OneTime uses IP addresses to analyze trends, administer our web site, and help diagnose problems with our servers. IP addresses are also used to gather broad demographic information and to prevent, investigate, and take actions in the case of suspected fraud or abuse. 

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small piece of data that a web server places on a user's computer. OneTime employs the use of cookies and web beacons to ensure that you do not see the same ad repeatedly, to track marketing promotions, to estimate and report audience size and traffic, and to customize and personalize your experience at OneTime.com.

Furthermore, OneTime may, from time to time, use outside media companies to display advertisements on our site. These ads may contain cookies and web beacons, which are collected and tracked by the outside media company. OneTime has no access to or control over these cookies.

Most web browsers provide users the ability to limit the use of cookies and web beacons by allowing users to adjust privacy settings. If a user has their cookies disabled, OneTime will still be accessible, however some sections of the web site will not perform as well as they normally would with cookies enabled.

**Links to Other Sites**

OneTime.com contains links to other web sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of every web site that collects personally identifiable information. 

**Security, Fraud, and Abuse**

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. OneTime regularly reviews these measures to better protect users. Occasionally information may be provided to OneTime fraudulently or by an individual unauthorized to provide such information. OneTime may use all information it collects for reasonable investigation and prosecution of suspected fraud and/or abuse. OneTime may provide all information it collects to third parties as necessary to comply with law enforcement requests or other legal requirements. 

OneTime does not ensure or warrant the security of any information transmitted to us over the Internet.

**Opting Out of Further Communications and Updating Personal Information**

OneTime.com subscribers may opt out of receiving future OneTime.com communications or update their personal information using any of the following methods:

  * Website: <http://www.onetime.com/signin>
  * Email: [help@onetime.com](mailto:help@onetime.com)
  * Mail: Smarter Travel Media LLC, Attn: OneTime Customer Service, 226 Causeway Street, Third Floor, Boston, MA 02114

To opt out of future communications from OneTime's partners, please contact the partner directly. For assistance with this, please contact OneTime's Customer Service: [help@onetime.com](mailto:help@onetime.com).

**Service and Partner Updates**

We may send our users service and partner announcements from time to time. Users are not able to unsubscribe from service announcements, which contain information about our services and partners, without opting-out of all OneTime newsletters. You may opt-out of receiving future communications; see the Opting-Out of Further Communications section below. 

We communicate with our users to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account via email, telephone, or postal mail. 

**Smarter Travel Media LLC Product**

OneTime.com is a product managed by Smarter Travel Media LLC. Smarter Travel Media LLC from time to time may compare, merge or append information collected on OneTime.com with data from one or more other sites managed by Smarter Travel Media LLC, its affiliate websites, its parent company, TripAdvisor LLC (including its affiliated websites) , and TripAdvisor's parent company, Expedia Inc LLC (including its affiliated websites). Similarly, information you provide on other Smarter Travel Media LLC managed sites may be compared, merged or appended to information you provide via OneTime.com.

**Business Assets**

As part of operations, OneTime may sell, transfer or merge particular businesses and/or other assets to a third party. As part of such a transaction, personal information users have provided to OneTime may be given to a third party. OneTime attempts to comply with all legislative and judicial orders. These orders will take precedence over the details stated in the policy above. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or your dealings with OneTime, please contact us using the contact information below.

**How we protect your information**

We want you to feel confident about using OneTime to plan and purchase your travel. While no Web site can guarantee security, we have implemented appropriate administrative, technical, and physical security procedures to help protect the information you provide to us.

**External Links**

OneTime links you to other Web sites. Please note that those Web sites do not operate under this Privacy Policy, and we are not responsible for their practices. We recommend you examine the privacy statements posted on those other Web sites to understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing personal information.

**Visiting our Web sites from outside the United States**

If you are visiting our Web site from outside the United States, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located and our central database is operated. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country, but please be assured that OneTime does take steps pursuant to laws in the United States to ensure that your privacy is protected. By using our services, you understand that your information may be transferred to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Policy. 

**Your California privacy rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please email [privacy@onetime.com](mailto:privacy@onetime.com)

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

OneTime may update this Privacy Policy in the future. We will notify our members about material changes to this Privacy Policy by either sending a notice to the e-mail address you provided to us or by placing a prominent notice on our Web site. 

**How you can contact us**

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at: 

Email: [privacy@onetime.com](mailto:privacy@onetime.com)

Smarter Travel Media LLC  
226 Causeway Street  
Third Floor  
Boston, MA 02114  
617-886-5555  
617-886-5501 (fax)
